{"1" : {
    "idquestion" : 1,
    "question" : "Which famous director won the Academy Award for Best Director for the movie \"The Godfather\" in 1972?",
    "a" : "Martin Scorsese",
    "b": "Francis Ford Coppola",
    "c" : "Steven Spielberg",
    "d" : "Quentin Tarantino",
    "correct" : "Francis Ford Coppola"
  },
  "2": {
    "idquestion" : 2,
    "question" : "Which 1980s movie, directed by Ridley Scott and starring Harrison Ford, is a classic science fiction film?",
    "a" : "E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial",
    "b": "Blade Runner",
    "c" : "Back to the Future",
    "d" : "The Terminator",
    "correct" : "Blade Runner"
  },
  "3" : {
    "idquestion" : 3,
    "question" : "Which 1994 film, directed by Quentin Tarantino, popularized the song \"Misirlou\" by Dick Dale?",
    "a" : "Pulp Fiction",
    "b": "Reservoir Dogs",
    "c" : "Kill Bill: Vol. 1",
    "d" :"Jackie Brown",
    "correct" : "Pulp Fiction"
  },
  "4" : {
    "idquestion" : 4,
    "question" : "Which of the following movies won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 2020?",
    "a" : "The Irishman",
    "b" : "Joker",
    "c" : "Parasite",
    "d" : "1917",
    "correct" : "Parasite"
  },
  "5" : {
    "idquestion" : 5,
    "question" : "In the movie \"Forrest Gump,\" what is the famous line Forrest says:\"Life is like a box of chocolates...\"?",
    "a" : "...you never know what you're gonna get.",
    "b" : "...it's full of surprises.",
    "c" : "...you have to savor every moment.",
    "d" : "...it's sweet and delightful.",
    "correct" : "...you never know what you're gonna get."
  },
  "6" :{
    "idquestion" : 6,
    "question" : "Which actor portrayed the iconic character James Bond in the 1970s film \"The Spy Who Loved Me\"?",
    "a" : "Roger Moore",
    "b" : "Sean Connery",
    "c" : "Timothy Dalton",
    "d" : "Pierce Brosnan",
    "correct" : "Roger Moore"
  },
  "7" : {
    "idquestion" : 7,
    "question" : "Who directed the 2014 science fiction film \"Interstellar\"?",
    "a" : "Christopher Nolan",
    "b" : "James Cameron",
    "c" : "Denis Villeneuve",
    "d" : "Ridley Scott",
    "correct" : "Christopher Nolan"
  },
  "8" : {
    "idquestion" : 8,
    "question" : "In the film \"The Silence of the Lambs,\" what is the name of the brilliant psychiatrist and cannibalistic serial killer?",
    "a" : "Norman Bates",
    "b" : "Michael Myers",
    "c" : "Hannibal Lecter",
    "d" : "Freddy Krueger",
    "correct" : "Hannibal Lecter"
  },
  "9":{
    "idquestion" : 9,
    "question" : "Which animated film from the 2000s tells the story of an ogre and his journey to rescue a princess?",
    "a" : "Finding Nemo",
    "b" : "Shrek",
    "c" : "Toy Story",
    "d" : "The Incredibles",
    "correct" : "Shrek"
  },
  "10": {
    "idquestion" : 10,
    "question" : "In the film \"Gladiator,\" who portrayed the Roman general Maximus Decimus Meridius?",
    "a" : "Brad Pitt",
    "b" : "Russell Crowe",
    "c" : "Leonardo DiCaprio",
    "d" : "Tom Cruise",
    "correct" : "Russell Crowe"
  },
  "11" : {
    "idquestion" : 11,
    "question" : "For which movie was Sylvester Stallone nominated for the Oscar for Best Actor?",
    "a" : "Stop! or my mom will shoot",
    "b" : "Demolition man",
    "c" : "first Blood",
    "d" : "Rocky",
    "correct" : "Rocky"
  },
  "12" : {
    "idquestion" : 12 ,
    "question" : "Which 1980s film features a group of kids searching for pirate treasure?",
    "a" : "Stand by Me",
    "b" : "The Goonies",
    "c" : "E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial",
    "d" : "Back to the Future",
    "correct" : "The Goonies"
  },
  "13" : {
    "idquestion" : 13,
    "question" : "Who directed the 2010 film \"Inception,\" which explores the concept of entering dreams?",
    "a" : "Quentin Tarantino",
    "b" : "Martin Scorsese",
    "c" : "James Cameron",
    "d" : "Christopher Nolan",
    "correct" : "Christopher Nolan"
  },
  "14" : {
    "idquestion" : 14,
    "question" : "Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1977?",
    "a" : "Network",
    "b" : "Rocky",
    "c" : "The Godfather Part II",
    "d" : "All the President's Men",
    "correct" : "Rocky"
  },
  "15" : {
    "idquestion" : 15,
    "question" : "In the movie \"The Departed,\" who plays the undercover cop Billy Costigan?",
    "a" : "Matt Damon",
    "b" : "Leonardo DiCaprio",
    "c" : "Mark Wahlberg",
    "d" : "Brad Pitt",
    "correct" : "Leonardo DiCaprio"
  },
  "16" : {
    "idquestion" : 16,
    "question" : "Which movie follows the adventures of a teenager who travels through time in a DeLorean?",
    "a" : "Back to the Future",
    "b" : "Ghostbusters",
    "c" : "The Terminator",
    "d" : "Ferris Bueller's Day Off",
    "correct" : "Back to the Future"
  },
  "17" : {
    "idquestion" :17,
    "question" : "Who portrayed the character of Tony Montana in the crime film \"Scarface\"?",
    "a" : "Marlon Brando",
    "b" : "Joe Pesci",
    "c" : "Robert De Niro",
    "d" : "Al Pacino",
    "correct" : "Al Pacino"
  },
  "18" : {
    "idquestion" : 18,
    "question" : "Which movie from the 2010s tells the story of a young woman who finds love while battling a life-threatening illness?",
    "a" : "The Fault in Our Stars",
    "b" : "Me Before You",
    "c" : "La La Land",
    "d" : "A Star is Born",
    "correct" : "The Fault in Our Stars"
  },
  "19" : {
    "idquestion" : 19,
    "question" : "In the film \"Jurassic Park,\" what type of animals do the main characters encounter?",
    "a" : "Dinosaurs",
    "b" : "Aliens",
    "c" : "Zombies",
    "d" : "Vampires",
    "correct" : "Dinosaurs"
  },
  "20" : {
    "idquestion" : 20,
    "question" : "Which 2016 film features a group of rebels stealing plans for the Death Star from the Galactic Empire?",
    "a" : "Star Wars: The Force Awakens",
    "b" : "Rogue One: A Star Wars Story",
    "c" : "Star Wars: The Last Jedi",
    "d" : "Solo: A Star Wars Story",
    "correct" : "Rogue One: A Star Wars Story"
  },
  "21" : {
    "idquestion" : 21,
    "question" : "Who directed the 1999 science fiction film \"The Matrix\"?",
    "a" : "Steven Spielberg",
    "b" : "James Cameron",
    "c" : "Ridley Scott",
    "d" : "The Wachowskis",
    "correct" : "The Wachowskis"
  },
  "22" : {
    "idquestion" : 22,
    "question" : "Which 2000s movie is about an animal with a passion for cooking who aspires to become a chef in a famous restaurant?",
    "a" : "Ratatouille",
    "b" : "Finding Nemo",
    "c" : "Madagascar",
    "d" : "Kung Fu Panda",
    "correct" : "Ratatouille"
  },
  "23" : {
    "idquestion" : 23,
    "question" : "In the film \"Die Hard,\" who plays the role of John McClane?",
    "a" : "Bruce Willis",
    "b" : "Arnold Schwarzenegger",
    "c" : "Sylvester Stallone",
    "d" : "Mel Gibson",
    "correct" : "Bruce Willis"
  },
  "24" : {
    "idquestion" : 24,
    "question" : "Which 2013 film features a young man who forms an unlikely friendship with an elderly woman in a nursing home, sharing stories from the past?",
    "a" : "The Notebook",
    "b" : "The Help",
    "c" : "The Best Exotic Marigold Hotel",
    "d" : "The Green Mile",
    "correct" : "The Best Exotic Marigold Hotel"
  },
  "25" : {
    "idquestion" : 25,
    "question" : "In the movie \"Avatar,\" directed by James Cameron, what is the name of the the main character?",
    "a" : "Miles Quaritch",
    "b" : "Jake Sully",
    "c" : "Grace Augustine",
    "d" : "Pandora",
    "correct" : "Jake Sully"
  },
  "26" : {
    "idquestion" : 26,
    "question" : "Which actor played the role of the Joker in the film \"The Dark Knight\"?",
    "a" : "Jack Nicholson",
    "b" : "Jared Let",
    "c" : "Heath Ledger",
    "d" : "Joaquin Phoenix",
    "correct" : "Heath Ledger"
  },
  "27" : {
    "idquestion" : 27,
    "question" : "Who directed the 1994 film \"The Shawshank Redemption,\" which is often ranked as one of the greatest movies of all time?",
    "a" : "Martin Scorsese",
    "b" : "Frank Darabont",
    "c" : "Steven Spielberg",
    "d" : "Paul Thomas Anderson",
    "correct" : "Frank Darabont"
  },
  "28" : {
    "idquestion" : 28,
    "question" : "In the film \"Eternal Sunshine of the Spotless Mind,\" who played the role of Joel Barish?",
    "a" : "Jim Carrey",
    "b" : "Johnny Depp",
    "c" : "Leonardo DiCaprio",
    "d" : "Tom Hanks",
    "correct" : "Jim Carrey"
  },
  "29" : {
    "idquestion" : 29,
    "question" : "Which 1980s movie, directed by John Hughes, follows a high school student's quest to skip school for a day of adventure in Chicago?",
    "a" : "Sixteen Candles",
    "b" : "Ferris Bueller's Day Off",
    "c" : "The Breakfast Club",
    "d" : "Pretty in Pink",
    "correct" : "Ferris Bueller's Day Off"
  },
  "30" : {
    "idquestion" : 30,
    "question" : "What is the name of the character played by Johnny Depp in the \"Pirates of the Caribbean\" film series?",
    "a" : "Captain Hook",
    "b" : "Captain Barbossa",
    "c" : "Blackbeard",
    "d" : "Captain Jack Sparrow",
    "correct" : "Captain Jack Sparrow"
  },
  "31": {
    "idquestion": 31,
    "question": "In the movie 'The Godfather,' who plays the role of Don Vito Corleone?",
    "a": "Robert De Niro",
    "b": "Marlon Brando",
    "c": "Al Pacino",
    "d": "Joe Pesci",
    "correct": "Marlon Brando"
  },
  "32": {
    "idquestion": 32,
    "question": "Which actor portrayed Batman in the trilogy directed by Christopher Nolan?",
    "a": "Christian Bale",
    "b": "Robert Downey Jr.",
    "c": "Hugh Jackman",
    "d": "Ben Affleck",
    "correct": "Christian Bale"
  },
  "33": {
    "idquestion": 33,
    "question": "Who portrayed James Bond in the 2006 film 'Casino Royale'?",
    "a": "Pierce Brosnan",
    "b": "Daniel Craig",
    "c": "Sean Connery",
    "d": "Roger Moore",
    "correct": "Daniel Craig"
  },    
  "34" : {
    "idquestion": 34,
    "question": "In which city does the movie 'La La Land' take place?",
    "a": "New York",
    "b": "Chicago",
    "c": "Los Angeles",
    "d": "San Francisco",
    "correct": "Los Angeles"
  },
  "35": {
    "idquestion": 35,
    "question": "Who portrayed Hermione Granger in the 'Harry Potter' film series?",
    "a": "Emma Stone",
    "b": "Emma Watson",
    "c": "Emma Roberts",
    "d": "Emily Blunt",
    "correct": "Emma Watson"
  },
  "36": {
    "idquestion": 36,
    "question": "In the movie 'The Matrix,' what is the famous phrase spoken by Morpheus to Neo?",
    "a": "'I'll be back!'",
    "b": "'May the Force be with you'",
    "c": "'Hasta la vista, baby'",
    "d": "'The red pill or the blue pill'",
    "correct": "'The red pill or the blue pill'"
  },
  "37": {
    "idquestion": 37,
    "question": "What is the name of Johnny Depp's character in Tim Burton's 'Alice in Wonderland' film series?",
    "a": "The Mad Hatter",
    "b": "The Cheshire Cat",
    "c": "The White Rabbit",
    "d": "The Grinch",
    "correct": "The Mad Hatter"
  },
  "38": {
    "idquestion": 38,
    "question": "In which Christopher Nolan film does a team of thieves steal information from people's minds while they dream?",
    "a": "'Inception'",
    "b": "'Interstellar'",
    "c": "'Dunkirk'",
    "d": "'The Prestige'",
    "correct": "'Inception'"
  },
  "39": {
    "idquestion":39,
    "question": "Which Disney animated film is based on Chinese folklore and follows the adventures of Mulan?",
    "a": "'Sleeping Beauty'",
    "b": "'Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs'",
    "c": "'Mulan'",
    "d": "'Beauty and the Beast'",
    "correct": "'Mulan'"
  },
  "40": {
    "idquestion": 40,
    "question": "What is the name of the character played by Marlon Brando in the movie 'Apocalypse Now'?",
    "a": "Don Vito Corleone",
    "b": "Colonel Walter E. Kurtz",
    "c": "Jor-El",
    "d": "Terry Malloy",
    "correct": "Colonel Walter E. Kurtz"
  },
  "41": {
    "idquestion": 41,
    "question": "Which director is known for his collaboration with actor Leonardo DiCaprio in films like 'Inception' and 'The Revenant'?",
    "a": "Christopher Nolan",
    "b": "Martin Scorsese",
    "c": "Quentin Tarantino",
    "d": "Steven Spielberg",
    "correct": "Christopher Nolan"
  },
  "42": {
    "idquestion": 42,
    "question": "In the film 'Citizen Kane,' what is the last word spoken by Charles Foster Kane?",
    "a": "Rosebud",
    "b": "Legacy",
    "c": "Rosewater",
    "d": "Citizen",
    "correct": "Rosebud"
  },
  "43": {
    "idquestion": 43,
    "question": "Which actor won an Academy Award for Best Actor for his role in the film 'There Will Be Blood'?",
    "a": "Joaquin Phoenix",
    "b": "Daniel Day-Lewis",
    "c": "Leonardo DiCaprio",
    "d": "Gary Oldman",
    "correct": "Daniel Day-Lewis"
  },
  "44": {
    "idquestion": 44,
    "question": "Who directed the movie 'The Shining' based on Stephen King's novel?",
    "a": "Stanley Kubrick",
    "b": "Alfred Hitchcock",
    "c": "David Lynch",
    "d": "Francis Ford Coppola",
    "correct": "Stanley Kubrick"
  },     
  "45": {
    "idquestion": 45,
    "question": "In the movie 'Gone with the Wind,' who plays the role of Rhett Butler?",
    "a": "Clark Gable",
    "b": "Humphrey Bogart",
    "c": "Gregory Peck",
    "d": "Cary Grant",
    "correct": "Clark Gable"
  },
  "46": {
    "idquestion": 46,
    "question": "Which legendary actor starred in the films 'Cool Hand Luke' and 'The Hustler'?",
    "a": "Marlon Brando",
    "b": "Paul Newman",
    "c": "James Dean",
    "d": "Humphrey Bogart",
    "correct": "Paul Newman"
  },
  "47": {
    "idquestion": 47,
    "question": "Who directed the 1979 science fiction horror film 'Alien'?",
    "a": "Steven Spielberg",
    "b": "Ridley Scott",
    "c": "George Lucas",
    "d": "James Cameron",
    "correct": "Ridley Scott"
  },
  "48": {
    "idquestion": 48,
    "question": "Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1994?",
    "a": "'Pulp Fiction'",
    "b": "'Forrest Gump'",
    "c": "'The Shawshank Redemption'",
    "d": "'Schindler's List'",
    "correct": "'Forrest Gump'"
  },
  "49": {
    "idquestion": 49,
    "question": "In the film 'Taxi Driver,' who plays the role of Travis Bickle?",
    "a": "Robert De Niro",
    "b": "Al Pacino",
    "c": "Dustin Hoffman",
    "d": "Jack Nicholson",
    "correct": "Robert De Niro"
  },
  "50": {
    "idquestion": 50,
    "question": "Which actor portrayed the character Hannibal Lecter in the film 'The Silence of the Lambs'?",
    "a": "Anthony Hopkins",
    "b": "Christopher Walken",
    "c": "Sean Connery",
    "d": "Jack Nicholson",
    "correct": "Anthony Hopkins"
  },
  "51": {
    "idquestion": 51,
    "question": "In the movie 'Fight Club,' what is the name of Brad Pitt's character?",
    "a": "Tyler Durden",
    "b": "John Wick",
    "c": "Travis Bickle",
    "d": "Tony Stark",
    "correct": "Tyler Durden"
  },
  "52": {
    "idquestion": 52,
    "question": "Which movie features a character named Norman Bates and the famous shower scene?",
    "a": "'Psycho'",
    "b": "'The Shining'",
    "c": "'The Exorcist'",
    "d": "'The Texas Chain Saw Massacre'",
    "correct": "'Psycho'"
  },
  "53": {
    "idquestion": 53,
    "question": "In the film 'A Clockwork Orange,' what is the protagonist's name?",
    "a": "Alex DeLarge",
    "b": "Jack Torrance",
    "c": "Travis Bickle",
    "d": "Wendy Torrance",
    "correct": "Alex DeLarge"
  },
  "54": {
    "idquestion": 54,
    "question": "Which iconic filmmaker directed the movies 'The Birds' and 'Vertigo'?",
    "a": "Alfred Hitchcock",
    "b": "Stanley Kubrick",
    "c": "Francis Ford Coppola",
    "d": "Martin Scorsese",
    "correct": "Alfred Hitchcock"
  },
  "55": {
    "idquestion": 55,
    "question": "In the film 'The Departed,' who plays the role of mob boss Frank Costello?",
    "a": "Robert De Niro",
    "b": "Alec Baldwin",
    "c": "Jack Nicholson",
    "d": "Martin Sheen",
    "correct": "Jack Nicholson"
  },
  "56": {
    "idquestion": 56,
    "question": "Which movie marked the directorial debut of actor Orson Welles and is often considered one of the greatest films of all time?",
    "a": "'Casablanca'",
    "b": "'Gone with the Wind'",
    "c": "'Citizen Kane'",
    "d": "'The Godfather'",
    "correct": "'Citizen Kane'"
  },
  "57": {
    "idquestion": 57,
    "question": "In the movie 'Blade Runner,' what is the name of the special unit of the police force responsible for hunting replicants?",
    "a": "Cyber Crimes Division",
    "b": "Replicant Enforcement Agency",
    "c": "Nexus Unit",
    "d": "Blade Runners",
    "correct": "Blade Runners"
  }, 
  "58": {
    "idquestion": 58,
    "question": "Which actor portrayed the character Michael Corleone in 'The Godfather' trilogy?",
    "a": "Marlon Brando",
    "b": "Al Pacino",
    "c": "Robert De Niro",
    "d": "Joe Pesci",
    "correct": "Al Pacino"
  },
  "59": {
    "idquestion": 59,
    "question": "In the movie 'The Prestige,' what is the stage name of Christian Bale's character?",
    "a": "The Great Danton",
    "b": "The Amazing Borden",
    "c": "The Illusionist",
    "d": "The Marvelous Magician",
    "correct": "The Great Danton"
  },
  "60": {
    "idquestion": 60,
    "question": "Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1972?",
    "a": "'The French Connection'",
    "b": "'Rocky'",
    "c": "'One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest'",
    "d": "'The Godfather'",
    "correct": "'The Godfather'"
  },
  "61": {
    "idquestion": 61,
    "question": "Who directed the science fiction film '2001: A Space Odyssey'?",
    "a": "George Lucas",
    "b": "Stanley Kubrick",
    "c": "Steven Spielberg",
    "d": "James Cameron",
    "correct": "Stanley Kubrick"
  },
  "62": {
    "idquestion": 62,
    "question": "In the movie 'The Grand Budapest Hotel,' what is the profession of Ralph Fiennes' character, Monsieur Gustave H.?",
    "a": "Concierge",
    "b": "Detective",
    "c": "Chef",
    "d": "Fashion Designer",
    "correct": "Concierge"
  },
  "63": {
    "idquestion": 63,
    "question": "Which film was the directorial debut of Jordan Peele and is a horror-thriller that addresses social issues?",
    "a": "'Hereditary'",
    "b": "'Get Out'",
    "c": "'A Quiet Place'",
    "d": "'Us'",
    "correct": "'Get Out'"
  },
  "64": {
    "idquestion": 64,
    "question": "In the film 'The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring,' who is the bearer of the One Ring?",
    "a": "Frodo Baggins",
    "b": "Gandalf",
    "c": "Aragorn",
    "d": "Sauron",
    "correct": "Frodo Baggins"
  },
  "65": {
    "idquestion": 65,
    "question": "Which movie features a group of magicians called 'The Four Horsemen' performing elaborate heists?",
    "a": "'Now You See Me'",
    "b": "'The Prestige'",
    "c": "'The Illusionist'",
    "d": "'The Great Debaters'",
    "correct": "'Now You See Me'"
  },
  "66": {
    "idquestion": 66,
    "question": "Who directed the epic historical drama film 'Schindler's List'?",
    "a": "Martin Scorsese",
    "b": "Steven Spielberg",
    "c": "Francis Ford Coppola",
    "d": "Quentin Tarantino",
    "correct": "Steven Spielberg"
  },    
  "67": {
    "idquestion": 67,
    "question": "In the movie 'No Country for Old Men,' what weapon does the antagonist Anton Chigurh use as his signature killing tool?",
    "a": "Katana",
    "b": "Machete",
    "c": "Pneumatic Bolt Gun",
    "d": "Crossbow",
    "correct": "Pneumatic Bolt Gun"
  },
  "68": {
    "idquestion": 68,
    "question": "Which actress won an Academy Award for her role in the film 'Black Swan'?",
    "a": "Natalie Portman",
    "b": "Scarlett Johansson",
    "c": "Jennifer Lawrence",
    "d": "Anne Hathaway",
    "correct": "Natalie Portman"
  },
  "69": {
    "idquestion": 69,
    "question": "Which film won the Academy Award for Best Picture in 1980?",
    "a": "'Ordinary People'",
    "b": "'Raging Bull'",
    "c": "'Kramer vs. Kramer'",
    "d": "'Apocalypse Now'",
    "correct": "'Ordinary People'"
  },
  "70": {
    "idquestion": 70,
    "question": "In the movie 'The Usual Suspects,' who is the mysterious criminal mastermind Keyser Söze?",
    "a": "Verbal Kint",
    "b": "Kaiser Soze",
    "c": "Jack Vincennes",
    "d": "Tyler Durden",
    "correct": "Verbal Kint"
  },
  "71": {
    "idquestion": 71,
    "question": "Which movie features a talented artist played by Leonardo DiCaprio who forges checks and assumes various identities?",
    "a": "American Psycho",
    "b": "The Wolf of Wall Street",
    "c": "Catch Me If You Can",
    "d": "The Great Gatsby",
    "correct": "Catch Me If You Can"
  },
  "72" : {
    "idquestion": 72,
    "question": "Who directed the film 'Apocalypse Now,' which is based on Joseph Conrad's novel 'Heart of Darkness'?",
    "a": "Francis Ford Coppola",
    "b": "Martin Scorsese",
    "c": "Oliver Stone",
    "d": "Steven Spielberg",
    "correct": "Oliver Stone"
  }
}

